Bariq Faylaq Noori

Administration Support, IT, HR, Security & Finance Officer



Personal Details

Full legal Name: Bariq Faylaq Noori

Marital status : Single
Nationality : Iraqi
Residency : Iraq

Date of Birth : 19 September 1994

Address : Baghdad

Mobile Tel : +9647814456664

+9647706962473

Email : <u>bariq.faylaq@yahoo.com</u>

Skype Address: bariq.faylaq

Language Skills: Fluent written and spoken communication in Arabic, English.

Introduction

I am a successful and highly respected Administration Accountant, IT, Procurement & Logistic Officer a competent, dynamic as highly motivated HR professional with excellent professional work of almost seven years experience supporting the Accounting, Finance, Procurement, HR, and Administration of multinational corporations doing business in Iraq. Through my life, both personal and professional, I have held myself to the highest standards of honesty and Integrity, Admin and Human Resource assistance for many tasks as Account Receivable Operations. Resolve discrepancies and research client issues. Balance accounts and review aged trial balances. Coordinate work with the CFO and HR manager in the preparation of financial reports, general ledger, forecasting, and HR issues. Prepare contracts & service contracts, negotiate employee benefits & process payroll for more than 5 projects. I love my work and actually I enjoy spending 12 plus hours a day ensuring all aspects of my work are at the highest possible standards. Unlike many of the accounting and finance professionals I have known, I maintain a personable and friendly demeanour with all my co-workers, regardless of color, creed, sex, race, or religion. I have often found myself acting in the capacity of communication and Human Recourse in addition to my regular work due to this friendly demeanor experience as HR Specialist and good assistant to operations management in complex and multi culture environment, possessing excellent communications and interpersonal skills seeking a challenging position in strategic management role with an organization which has a culture of teamwork and ample opportunities for individual growth, the organization where pure talent & capabilities are appreciated, I can be an enormous asset for organizational growth and development and a willingness to tackle any task with courage and conviction. I am Integrity, Impartial, Honest and Truthful. I could work as security staff member who are not afraid to think creatively, to be more proactive, flexible and responsive for any aid assistance especially at the influx crisis in my country IRAQ or in any other country round the world. Also I am looking forward to many more years in my chosen professions, I hope to join working with American or British Embassy or any of UN Agencies.

Career History

Starting from 1 May 2018 Till 31 March 2019

IT & Logistic Officer, IMMAP (Information Management and Mine Action Programs).

Under iMMAP / IRAQ program of provision of information management services for UNMAS / Iraq Program I have been contracted as logistic and IT Offcier based in Baghdad, of the transportation process for staff movement, promote and share ideas for improvement of the transportation and provide facilities, arrange the technical aspect of procurement of equipment, furniture and office supplies, tracking all assets, provide logistical to support administration and HR of the organization and preparation of all workshops, meetings and events, maintain effective and positive internal contacts with iMMAP Regional officers & staff, external contacts with national and local government officials as (MOI / Ministry of Interior) to follow up on obtaining Green Zone ID Badges and with (MoFA/Ministry of Foreign Affairs to follow up on Visa status for all international staff, coordinate with (NGOs / International non-Governmental Organizations), reporting donor agency officials, vendors, media, and the general public, represent the iMMAP project team with partners, and participate in local community activities.

Moreover, I have been contracted as IT & Logistic Officer to be responsible for the set-up development and maintenance for iMMAP projects in Baghdad' follow up on security procedure for the system files, solve problems regarding operating systems, replace computer hardware as required, provide supportive documentation; including procedural documentation, assisting to develop staff capacity through guidance, training and technical support.

Starting from 14 February 2014 till 31 Jan 2018

Finance Officer, Muslim Aid Serving Humanity.

Muslim Aid is an INGO / in Iraq- Baghdad wining several contract agreements to serve many of UN Agencies, I have been contracted under UNHCR, as the administration department is backbone of any organization. I have been an effective administrator in many tasks with team up to develop the organization. Also I am the link among various departments to ensure the smooth flow of information from one project to the other as follows:

- 1- Project Cash Assistance / UNHCR 4 Pillars in Various Cities in IRAQ
- 2- Project Core Relieve Items / UNHCR
- 3- Project Rehabilitation Center / UNHCR
- 4- Project Distributions Food / WFP in Salaheldin, Babil, Dayala, Mosul, Alanbar
- 5- Project for Health Care & Project of Medic Training / WHO
- 6- Project of Primary Schools Constructions / UNCIEF
- Responsible for issuing and prepare a cheques for the beneficiaries under 4 projects of Cash Assistance.
- Checked bills, PO (Purchase Order), invoices, receipts submitted for payment with special attention to submission and providing of completed documents, procedures & guidelines including specific grant/donor requirements are followed.
- Prepared Cash Distribution Vouchers (CDV), cheques, as well as preparation of (CRV) Cash Received Vouchers, prepare Journal Voucher (JV) of expenses report for training, procurement & travel advances and operation advances...etc.
- Coordinate to support emergency projects with most procurement and technical support activities as required.
- Ensured proper budget coding and ensure approvals from authorized persons are granted.
- Assisted in preparation of monthly salary payroll for more than 120 staff member under many Agencies.
- Petty Cash vouchers, receipts, monthly inventory & reconciliation for both Cash & Bank..
- Keep a scan copy for all supporting documents and organize the archive files in proper way.
- Registration of all financial data entry in FundEz system.
- Responsible of data entry for Assets with accounting the depreciation for the equipment used for each project.
- Supporting Local Area Network (Wire and Wireless), repairing and installing hardware parts
- Prepare all the invoices (FLA) for WFP and follow up on amendment contract.
- Review and verify all documentation and have them ready for auditing in both internal & external.
- Support the asset management in the office
- Monitor and maintain office supplies and assure timely provision of office equipment and stationary
- Provide administrative support to receive, inspect & verify incoming equipment supplies & delivery schedule to users.
- Assist in tagging all furniture/equipment upon receipt from the supplier and track movement of furniture piece.
- Provide administrative support to facilitate physical assets verification, and provide office management services.
- Collect information on shipments, customs clearance arrangements, prepare documents for (received/sent)• Timely processing of travel visa requests and other documentation from the relevant embassies and follow up on Issuance of residence VISA for all international staff members
- Organization of shipments, customs clearance arrangements, preparation of documents for shipments (received/sent), Preparation of all necessary documentation, implementation of follow-up actions.

- Administrative support in coordination with local government to conferences, workshops, retreats and other programme or project activity as required, and issue MOFA diplomatic ID cards for all international staff members.
- Provide administrative support to conferences, workshops, retreats and office management, Maintain filing system ensuring safekeeping of confidential materials, Ensure timely maintenance for office premises and repairs
- Coordinate with cleaning services to ensure daily cleaning of the office
- Ensure minor furniture repairs, troubleshooting and adjustment of locks of cabinets, drawers, closets, desks and door locks, Maintain all records of the repair and maintenance works conducted in the office, Report all defects, malfunctions and damages in the office and offer solutions to the Operations Manager or other key operations staff, Drive office vehicles for the transport of authorized personnel when needed, and drive both non-armored and armored vehicles.
- Provide support for effective administrative control in the office and assist office staff in filing, photocopying
- Assist in the mailing and distribution of publications and payment of bills, as required.

06 / 2013 till 12 / 2013

Administration Assistance, Dynamax (International Communications Company).

I have worked as Administration Assistance at Dynamax Company. as a Private Company for Information / IZ Baghdad (International Communications Company) I have brought good organize and clarity to an extremely difficult dealing with multiple currencies banking and funding in Iraq for duties as follows:

- Responsible party for accountability and reconciliation of cash and credit based system.
- Generate bilingual reporting and communication related funding as weekly performance.
- Process journals entries in accordance with established policies and procedures.
- Registration all financial movements in based system including all the staff payroll payments.
- Transferred amount and be confirmed of amount handed to the right mandate person including the supporting documents as with an effective administration the organization will run professionally and smoothly
- Prepare monthly payment compliance report and quarterly graphs, Processed, reviewed and audited payroll and payroll reports, Improved efficiency by utilizing all applicable functions of the payroll system.
- Assist training staff on First Aid & Safe Security, provide general administrative assistance & clerical services.
- Liaise with customer services / sales on all issues pertaining to disputes on invoices and receive credit notes.

05/2012 to 12/2012

Communication Assistance (Cabling) at EOD Technology

As a communication assistant I followed my entrepreneurial spirit, Using the skills and relationships built through good cooperation with malty cultures in country, I teamed up with an exceptional group and under expat American supervision of likeminded to hand me the duties as follows:

- Follow instructions from managers to prepare the cables needed and be responsible for running new cabling in new or existing buildings specially at Basmayah area, install and configure new software and hardware parts.
- Support company applications, web applications, corporate intranet and corporate public website.
- Support to Local Area Network (Wire and Wireless), repairing and installing hardware parts, upgrading their capacity.
- Resolve technical issues related to office equipment, such as Laptop, PC, printers, projector, monitors, etc.
- Resolve software incidents related email software, internet explorer, desktop operating systems and company software.
- Termination and testing of new cabling and responsible for testing and troubleshooting of cable.
- Demonstrates the initiative and creativity for self-development within and outside of the company (fields).
- Prepare the attendance timesheet for the local national staff and submitted as a daily to the supervisor.
- Communicate and interpret what's required to help the American supervisor through the work at field.
- Good personal & professional moral and ethical standards to deal at work with all staff. I bring the high level systems integration to the marketplace where rapid technological growth is leading to a lack of cohesive integration, security, and sustainability in voice and data networks.

06/2011 to 12/2011

Accountant (Trainer), Anhar Dubai Company for Electronic.

As the first job I start working to have an offered a position of accountant to do works as follows:

- Manage all accounts as daily cash logs, all income and expenditure tracking of Anhar Dubai Company.
- Prepare the hand receipts for vendors and suppliers.
- prepare report as weekly inventory for all storage good including the new procurements.
- update the personal files for all staff and have a complete personal documents for each employee.

Oualifications

Below listed are my key qualifications, I have worked with a wide range of software, hardware, and systems.

- Microsoft Office & All Generations of Windows
- Adobe Photoshop Alameer Financial System FundEz Financial System QuickBooks System
- Good Communications with Iraqi Government to apply for visas or any other cases
- Online research and developing relationships. Both Cash and Accrual based accounting
- Create various forms with logo as required for work
- IT Services Professional, Grant user's access to company databases, Install & configure technology equipment.
- Testing and troubleshooting of wiring problems & computers with all software and networks.
- Translation and interpret from Arabic to English and versa vice.
- Training and understanding of international regulations and policies with regards to Administration, Mine Action Training, Human Resources, Financial accounting, Procurement, Workers and human rights rules at work.

Education

I have consistently done well in my scholastic life, achieving the target simultaneously both of my secondary school & Diploma, My major skills had included the English language, IT Sciences, Administrations Business, and Accounting.

- 09/2008 – 06/2011 : High school (major in science technology), Al Rafidain School, Baghdad, Iraq.

- 06/2010 – 10/2010 : Course in English Language and Correspondence

- 09/2011 – 06/2012 : ICT science technology, Al Mustansiriya University. Baghdad, Iraq / only one-year study : Engineering Architecture, University of Technology, Iraq- Baghdad / only one-year study

Interests

My interests include the follows:

- Education I believe that one should never stop learning and I put forth a specific effort to learn new things each day and expand my vision or enhance my abilities in both professional and personal worlds.
- Travel Interesting to join a team that creates unique and socially responsible travel experiences, providing services beyond expectations, I am a person who will travel and work anywhere at a moment's notice
- Music Music is my metronome to set the tempo of my life, I listen to classical and symphonic pieces when I am thinking deeply and western pop (1980s) when I just need energy to complete my tasks.

References

Name : Ranj Omar Zahd

Title : ICT Operation Associate / UNAMI

Name : Jaylan Hikmat Abdulwahab Agha

Title : HR Manager / NCCI

Email Address: <u>jaylanagha@yahoo.com</u> Phone # : +964 (0) 770 025 8285

Name : Salim Al Haleem

Title : Field Security Assistant / UNAMI

Name : Omar Farooq Fadhil / Muslim Aid

Title : Cashier / Muslim Aid

Email Address: alnouriomar@yahoo.com Phone # : +964 (0) 790 231 6353

Name : Perry Metaxas

Title : Senior Investigation Officer / UNHCR

Email Address: <u>metaxas@unhcr.org</u> Phone # : +41 79 249 3474 / Office +41 22 739 8369

Name : Omar Ryath Sadoon Al Mafraji

Title : Eng. ICT & Cisco Information Technology / UNDP

Email Address: Omar.almufraji@gmail.com Phone # :+964 (0) 770 629 2540

Name : Javier Manrique

Title : Information Management Officer – Team Leader / **iMMAP**Email Address : jmanrique@immap.org Phone # : +964 (0) 7834960440